TimeTrade Systems, Inc. DBA Engageware and SilverCloud LLC DBA Engageware (collectively, “Engageware”) respects your privacy and values your trust. We are committed to ensuring that the personal information stored by our systems is suitably protected and used appropriately. This Privacy Statement describes the treatment and handling of all personal information collected by the Engageware website at [engageware.com](https://engageware.com/), including all related pages and landing pages, and/or by the use of Engageware’s services, including:

* What personally identifiable information is collected;
* How Engageware may use the personally identifiable information and with whom and when this information may be shared with third parties;
* Your rights to your personal information and how you can submit a request to view, remove, change, or transfer the collected personal information; and
* To whom questions regarding this Privacy Statement should be directed.

By using this website, you agree to comply with and be bound by this Privacy Statement and the Terms and Conditions of Use published at [engageware.com/terms-of-use/](https://engageware.com/terms-of-use/) (the “terms”). This Privacy Statement is incorporated into those Terms, and capitalized terms used, but not defined herein, have the meanings ascribed to them in the Terms.

**PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT CAREFULLY, AND PLEASE CHECK THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT FREQUENTLY, AS ENGAGEWARE RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AT ANY TIME WITHOUT NOTICE. BY ACCESSING THE WEBSITES OR THE SERVICES AFTER THE “LAST UPDATED” DATE SET FORTH BELOW, YOU ARE DEEMED TO CONSENT TO OUR THEN-CURRENT PRIVACY STATEMENT.**

##### 1\. Definitions

“**SMB**” refers to Engageware’s Personal, Professional, Workgroup, Individual, or Business Edition SaaS offerings. These offerings are for individuals and businesses or groups that require one-to-one appointment scheduling functionality or appointment routing. The SMB service is owned and operated by Engageware and sold on a per Subscriber basis. Terms of use for the SMB SaaS offering are detailed [here](https://engageware.com/smb-terms-of-service/).

“**Scheduler for Enterprise**” refers to Engageware’s SaaS product offering for larger businesses or organizations that require high volume scheduling, configurable interfaces and complex business rules. Scheduler for Enterprise is licensed under the terms and conditions set forth in our agreement with our Subscriber.

“**Subscriber**” is a single customer of the services provided by Engageware.

“**User**” is any person or device that connects to services hosted by Engageware on behalf of a Subscriber.

“**Visitor**” is any person or device that connects to the websites.

##### 2\. Use of Information Gathered by Engageware During Registration for Services or Other General Inquiries.

When you visit Engageware’s website for information regarding our products, promotions, employment opportunities or to register to use Engageware’s services, Engageware may gather information about you such as your name, business type, contact information, email address, IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses, payment method, and billing address information. If you disclose any personal data to us, you consent to our processing and use of such personal data in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Information may be used: a) for operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Engageware website b) contact you directly regarding Engageware services, career opportunities and/or to respond to your inquiries; or c) provide invoicing of the subscribed services. Any emails sent by Engageware will only be sent in accordance with this Privacy Statement.  
  
Engageware does not sell, rent, or lease its customer lists to third parties.

##### 3\. Credit Card Transactions

Online credit card payments related to SMB subscriptions are processed by a PCI certified payment processing vendor utilizing secure, encrypted payment card processing methods. Financial information will not be shared with any party not directly involved with billing of the services.

##### 4\. Use of Information

Engageware services allows Subscribers to collect information from a User for the purpose of providing the services. As a function of the services, Subscribers may customize the data that is collected from Users. Typically, the data collected is: First & Last Name, Email Address and Telephone number. Pursuant to best practices and privacy regulations, Subscribers should limit the amount of personally identifiable information collected to only that which is strictly necessary. A Subscriber should never ask for, and a User should never provide, sensitive information such as a credit card number or government identification number via the Engageware services

Except as specified elsewhere in this Policy Statement, Engageware considers all User information collected by Engageware on behalf of a Subscriber to be the proprietary information of the applicable Subscriber. _Accordingly, all User personal information is controlled by the Subscriber and is subject to the Subscriber’s privacy policy and practices, which may differ from this policy._

Engageware will retain the information collected by our Subscribers until the Subscriber requests its removal or the Subscriber terminates its relationship with Engageware. In either case Engageware will modify the collected data to be unreadable and unrecoverable.

Engageware employees may periodically access Subscriber data solely for administrative purposes, application support, to improve systems efficiency, add enhancements, and/or compile aggregated reports for trend analysis.

Any/all aggregated research results will be de-identified and will not contain any personably identifiable information (such as a User’s name, email address or phone number) or Subscriber specific information, such as name, resource, workflow or other usage details. Aggregated research results that contain no user-specific or subscriber-specific information may be shared with third parties.

With a Subscriber’s written permission, Engageware may use the User information collected on behalf of the Subscriber to perform surveys of Users and conduct research and analytics in such areas as product user experience, functionality and effectiveness. Research results may be shared with the Subscriber.

Engageware uses third-party service providers who work on our behalf and who are bound by contract to keep all information confidential and use the information solely to carry out the services that they are performing for us. For example, Engageware uses third party service providers to assist with the following: Hosting of the application servers and collected data and sending appointment confirmations, reminder e-mails and text/SMS messages.

Engageware will disclose information collected by a Subscriber (without notice if required to do so by law), if, in good faith, Engageware deems that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with applicable law or comply with legal process served on Engageware; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Engageware; or, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Subscribers, Users or Visitors of Engageware, or the public at large.

Unless otherwise prohibited by applicable law, a disclosure request by a legal or governmental authority shall be promptly communicated to the Subscriber, i.e., data owner.

##### 5\. Confidentiality of Service Data

Engageware internally classifies all scheduling, appointment and knowledge base information collected from or on behalf of a Subscriber as confidential and proprietary to the Subscriber. Engageware will never share a Subscriber’s data with any third party outside the scope of Engageware’s services.

Engageware will not share a User’s information with anyone except the applicable Subscriber or a third-party service provider performing services on behalf of Engageware. A Subscriber can only view information relating to User information in its instance of services application.

##### 6\. Links to Other Websites

Other websites and applications not under the direct control of Engageware are not governed by this Privacy Statement. Emails generated by Subscribers as part of the Engageware services may contain links to enable Users to visit other websites. Be aware that Engageware does not have any control over the target website and cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that a User provides while visiting them. Caution should be exercised when visiting unknown websites, and the privacy statement applicable to the website in question should be reviewed prior to use.

##### 7\. Children

Children should request permission from their parent or guardian prior to sending personal information online. Engageware does not intentionally collect any personal information from individuals under the age of 13. No part of Engageware’s website is structured to attract anyone under the age of 13. If a child has provided Engageware or a Engageware Subscriber with personal information via the websites or services and the parent or guardian would like this information removed from the Subscriber’s data, the parent or guardian of that child should contact the Subscriber and ask that the data be removed from their records. If further assistance is needed, contact Engageware directly at privacy@engageware.com and we will use reasonable efforts to assist in the deletion of the child’s personal information.

##### 8\. Information Automatically Collected

For user experience, analytical and support purposes, Engageware collects information about the systems that connect to our websites and services. Examples of this type of information include the IP address and type of Internet Browser and/or computer operating system used in the connection, which pages or functions within the application were accessed, and/or the domain name of the website and/or Internet Service Provider linked to our website or services. In addition, Engageware may collect general usage statistics and provide them to prospective advertisers or partners. This information is collected in aggregate form and does not include any personal information about specific Users, Subscribers or Visitors.

##### 9\. Mobile Applications and Devices

Engageware services are accessible via any supported internet connected web browser. This Privacy Statement is applicable to all Subscribers, Users and Visitors connected via a supported mobile device browser.

##### 10\. Internet Browser Cookies

A browser cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs. When any web browser connects to a Engageware provided website or service, the websites and services utilize browser cookies to a) provide a customizable and personalized experience, such as personal site preferences; b) record User session-specific information, such as which pages within the application were accessed; c) provide application session control to the servers hosting the application; and d) determine the device/browser type being used and its approximate geo-location. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer. _Disabling the support of browser cookies is not recommended: non-use of cookies may lead to reduced functionality and or an unsatisfactory user experience_

##### 11\. Security

Engageware’s website and services have reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in place designed to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation, or destruction. Engageware utilizes industry adopted server and database security measures, including encryption of personal data over public networks. Engageware also limits its employee’s access to personal information. Despite these protections, no information system is 100% secure, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information at all times.

##### 12\. Privacy Shield, Rights of EU Data Subjects & International Data Transfers from the European Economic Area (EEA)

TimeTrade Systems, Inc. DBA Engageware complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework(s) (Privacy Shield) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. TimeTrade Systems, Inc. DBA Engageware has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such information. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000000rjAAA)

Engageware respects an EEA individual’s rights to access personal information about them, and to limit use and disclosure of their personal information. Engageware has limited ability to access information our Subscribers and Users submit to our services, however, if you wish to request access, to limit use, or to limit disclosure, please provide the name of the Engageware Subscriber you interacted with. We will refer your request to that Subscriber and will support them as needed in responding to your request or you can contact the Subscriber directly

Engageware is accountable for personal information that it receives and subsequently transfers to third parties. If third parties that process personal information on our behalf do so in a manner that does not comply with the Privacy Shield Principles, we are accountable, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Individuals in the EEA may submit inquiries or complaints related to our processing of personal information under the Privacy Shield Framework directly to us at the e-mail address listed below in Section 16. In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Engageware, Inc. maintains an independent mechanism to investigate unresolved Privacy Shield complaints regarding our compliance to the Privacy Shield Principles. If we have not been able to successfully resolve your inquiry or complaint and you are based in the EU, you may raise your inquiry or complaint to JAMS ADR at [www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. In addition, as further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you in order to address residual complaints not resolved by any other means.

Engageware privacy practices are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and as such Engageware is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the FTC.

##### 13\. Requests to View, Remove, Change, or Transfer Your Personal Information Collected by Engageware

To Opt-Out from receiving Engageware announcements of certain information you can use the “unsubscribe” links in the email messages. To view, remove, change, or transfer the personal information collected by the websites, please send a written request detailing your desired action to privacy@engageware.com, or you may send the request to:

Data Privacy & Compliance  
Engageware  
100 Ames Pond Drive STE100  
Tewksbury MA 01876

##### 14\. Requests to View, Remove, Change, or Transfer Your Personal Information Collected By a Subscriber.

As noted above, Engageware considers all User information collected by Engageware on behalf of a Subscriber to our services, to be the proprietary information of the applicable Subscriber. A Subscriber may share your information pursuant to their own privacy policies. _To initiate a request to modify the collected information from a Subscriber’s data set, you must contact the Subscriber (the company you interacted with, via the Engageware services) and request the desired action._ The Subscriber should have provided you with the appropriate contact information during the interaction. If you are unable to resolve your request with the Subscriber, please provide the name of the Engageware Subscriber who you interacted with to Engageware. We will refer your request to that Subscriber and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

##### 15\. Residents of The State of California (California Consumer Protection Act, CCPA)

If you are a resident of California you have additional data rights pursuant to sections 1798.110, 1798.115, and 1798.125 of the CCPA. Please reference sections; 2, 5, 9 & 11 of this Privacy Statement for the categories and description of the data collected and its usage. Sections 14, 15 & 17 present available remedies if you would like to add, change or remove your data or if you believe that your data is not being used appropriately. _Note that Engageware does not sell, trade or use your information for compensation or for other considerations to, or with, any 3rd parties._

##### 16\. Contacting Us

Please direct any questions or requests regarding our Privacy Statement to our privacy coordinator at privacy@engageware.com, or contact us at 1-877-884-9224

_Last reviewed 09/09/2022_
